Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Motion Pictures Documenting Swimming
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, motion pictures documenting swimming
1935-1998
RU 990
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12
(13 motion pictures)
The rmaterials consist of videotapes created by the Department of Athletics documenting swimming at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Department of Athletics, Yale University, 2005-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Related Archival Materials
The International Swimming Hall of Fame online video archive: http://www.ishof.org/video_archive/index.htm dates back to the 1920s and contains footage of Yale swimming and diving meets from the 1960s. Visit the site to learn more.
Scope and Contents
The rmaterials consist of videotapes created by the Department of Athletics documenting swimming at Yale.
College athletes; College sports; Swimming; Motion pictures (visual works); Videotapes; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students; Yale University -- Swimming; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Swimming films, 1935-1977; Accession 2008-A-053
  - Mereersburg, Macionis, Metcalf, 1935-1956; film reel (16mm) (Box 1)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 1U)
  - 1938 relay: Noonan, Perryman, Duncan; 1939: Goode, Hough, 1938-1939; film reel (16mm) (Box 2)
  - 3rd International Dual Swimming Meet, Tokyo, Japan, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 3U)
  - ABC Wide World of Sports, AAU Swimming Championship [commercially-produced], 1963; 1 (Box 4)
  - Harvard, 1967?; 2 (Box 5–6)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copies, 2 (Box 5U–6U)
  - Princeton, 1967?; 2 (Box 7–8)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copies, 2 (Box 7U–8U)
  - Mollie Smith and the clock, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 9U)
  - U.S./international swim meet, 1963 December 6 (Box 10)
    - Duplicating master
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 10U)
- Swimming videotapes, 1998; Accession 2006-A-068
  - "100 Years of Swimming," 5 videotapes (VHS), 1998 October (Box 1–5)